Garret Krawchison

Full Stack Developer

My Site https://floridapropertymap.com
GitHub https://codepen.io/g2g
Jacksonville, Florida

5+ Years Web Development • JavaScript • PHP • C# • Vue.js • Vuex • Laravel • MySQL • PostgreSQL • PostGIS • HTML5 • Git • NPM • Bootstrap • Tailwind • SCSS • Debian • nginx • ArcGIS • MapLibre

INTRODUCTION

Hello, I am a Full Stack Developer with a deep background in web development, SQL, as well as GIS and geospatial programming. I have a track record of delivering successful projects and creative solutions, implementing a solid understanding of front-end and back-end development, object-oriented programming (OOP), and relational database design.

During my last five years as Full Stack Engineer for Leonard's, I led development efforts creating new tools, services, and web solutions, such as the Digital ID app (available in Apple Store and Google Play) and a Photographer Schedule Calendar. In my role, I helped to fine-tune and optimizing relational databases and websites for optimal performance. Creating front-end tools with easy user experience, I focus on clean, intuitive design, with details to meet or exceed expectations.

As lead developer on the Photographer Schedule Calendar (via https://schooladmin.leonards.com), I created a new system to coordinate events for hundreds of photographers in 800+ schools in Florida, contributing significantly to overall company operations. This allowed for easy coordination and notifications of upcoming events for photographers and the clients.

At Leonard's, I also led development for https://digitalid.leonards.com, building from scratch a digital ID application for 20,000+ students actively used in schools across Florida. I built this using a phone-verification system for students to claim their school IDs using their phone number. Using the administration panel, school principles and other school personnel were able to broadcast SMS notifications to students, which was based on the Twilio PHP API.

In my background as a GIS Analyst, I have had the opportunity to work at NextEra Energy, CSX Transportation, and other industry leaders, driving new company innovations and GIS services. Most recently, I produced my own interactive mapping site https://floridapropertymap.com. It features data analytics for all 20 million land parcels, businesses, and census layers across Florida. All data is completely self-hosted using PostgreSQL and a vector tile service on my own personal VPS.

I would like to thank you for the opportunity, and look forward to working on new innovative products and software solutions in the future.

Best regards,

Garret Krawchison

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Leonard's StudioSt. Augustine, FLSenior Systems EngineerOct 2020 – Jul 2023

- Led Full Stack development and project lead on multiple new systems and products, maintained site servers, and actively engaged with team members to develop new services to drive company productivity.
- Oversaw development of new sites resulting in a 25+% increase in total school contracts and over 20,000 app users.
- Developed schedule system, organizing hundreds of events for hundreds photographers across Florida schools each month.
- Created Digital ID app used in schools throughout Florida. Also, created admin site for schools to manage student IDs.
- Triaged website, database errors and provided regular server maintenance. Optimized relational databases for

performance.

• Mentored new employees and promoted an easy-to-read, Object-Oriented Programming style.

Full Stack Developer Dec 2018 – Oct 2020

- Created commercial sites with custom payment forms using Authorize.net API. Developed administrative sites used in 800+ schools across Florida to manage a large database of students, users, orders, and more.
- Developed API services and back-end MySQL relational databases, functions, procedures, triggers, full-text searches.
- Publish IIS services in C# and REST services. Developed custom e-mail queue system in MySQL. Custom logging system.

Tech: Vue, Laravel, PHP, JavaScript, MySQL, SCSS, Tailwind, C#, JSON, IIS, Debian, Apache, Nginx, Git, GitLab, Jira

Heery International / CSX Contractor GIS Analyst

Jacksonville, FL

Jul 2011 – Mar 2017

- Guided successful project implementations, creating new automation and tools, using Oracle SQL, Python, and ArcGIS toolsuite.
- Work with teams and senior leadership to develop and contribute to the Positive Train Control (PTC) team responsible for meeting railroad safety regulations goals. Created production workflow and SQL to process, QA/QC, and publish PTC data.
- Deployed high accuracy mapping services, layer maintenance, and company reports for 24,000 miles of railroad track.

Tech: Python, Oracle T/SQL, ArcPy, ArcMap, ArcInfo, ArcToolbox, ArcSDE databases

NextEra Energy Resources (FPL Energy)

Juno Beach, FL

GIS Analyst

May 2008 – Jul 2011

- Provided mapping services for the leading renewable energy generator in North America, and supporting a land lease team with hundreds of agents with lease status and mapping analysis.
- Created maps for site-suitability and electrical engineers showing energy facilities, wind farms, solar farms, environmental impacts, and electric distribution systems.
- Developed novel FAA Wind Turbine data process to map and analyse new proposed wind farm sites. Automated processes to generate and streamline maps for 200+ pipeline projects.
- Managed the NextEra Quarterly publication used to communicate company progress to stakeholders and executives.

Lockwood, Andrews, and Newnam

Fort Worth, TX

GIS Analyst

Jun 2006 – Apr 2008

- Provided GIS and mapping needs for multiple new road and highway expansion projects for TXDOT.
- Supported Environmental Impact Analysis, Alternative Route studies, RFPs, public meetings, eminent domain appraisals.

Coleman and Associates
GIS Technician
Sep 2005 – Jun 2006

EDUCATION

University of North Texas

Denton, TX

Bachelor's of Science, Geography Major + Biology Minor

2001 - 2005

Florida State College at Jacksonville

Jacksonville, FL

Technical Certificate, Computer Programming in C#

2015 - 2017

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Florida Property Map at https://floridapropertymap.com. Using MapLibre, PostGIS and vector tiles, the site delivers property and business data statewide across Florida. All data is hosted locally using vector tiles served with Martin from a PostgreSQL database. Scale ranges are handled using a custom layer algorithm and custom layer classes.